SQL Keywords:

INSERT - put data into a data table
INTO - name of the table to put data into is next
BOOKS - the table which the data is being put
(Title, year, pages) - the list of fields receiving data
VALUES - keyword signifying the values are next

SELECT * FROM books; retrieve all records from a data table called books

SELECT - create a dataset based on data from this database
* - shorthand for every field in the data table
FROM - tells the server that the table from where we want the information is next

1. Asking specifically for certain fields rather than asking for all
2. Putting conditions on the records which are returned

SELECT title, year, isbn FROM books WHERE title=“The Wind In The Willows”

Give me the title, year and isbn from the BOOKS table for all books with the given title

Two values for the same field: WHERE title=‘The Wind In The Willows’ OR title=‘It Happened One Night’

Two fields: WHERE year=205 AND publisher=‘Sony’

A range: WHERE year >=2000 AND year<= 2015

WILDCARD - %
SELECT * FROM books WHERE title LIKE ’T%’
SELECT * FROM books WHERE title LIKE ’%willows’
SELECT * FROM books WHERE title LIKE ’%willows%’
SELECT * FROM books WHERE title LIKE ’T%willows%’

UPLOADING DATA:

UPDATE books SET title=‘More Windy and More Willowy’
UPDATE - keyword for editing a row or rows in the datable
SET - keyword signifying that the new fields and values are next

Update only the row we want with a unique value

UPDATE books SET title=‘More Windy and More Willowy’ WHERE title=‘The Wind In The Willows’

DELETING DATA:

DELETE FROM books; delete every single row in the books table
SELECT * FROM books WHERE title LIKE ‘%T’ and available=1
DELETE FROM books WHERE title=‘More Windy and More Willowy’